Renaissance architecture photograph collection (France-Germany)
Yale University Arts Library
Renaissance architecture photograph collection (France-Germany)
1900-2005
VRC 34.2
Yale University Arts Library
13.75
33 boxes (Boxes 16-49 of 136)
Collection consists of black and white and color reproductions of Renaissance architecture. Section II includes France and Germany. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by country. Further sub-divided by location, building type, and building name.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of black and white and color reproductions of Renaissance architecture. Section II includes France and Germany. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Architecture, Renaissance; Photographs; Reproductions
- Architecture: Renaissance II. (Box 16)
  - France., 1458 (Box 16)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
    - General architects., 56 (Box 16)
      - Blondel, J. F., 1 (Box 16)
      - Boffrand, G., 1 (Box 16)
      - Boullee, Etienne-Louise., 5 (Box 16)
      - Cousin, Jean, 1490-1560., 1 (Box 16)
      - Du Cerceau, Jacques Androuet, 1510-1585., 9 (Box 16)
      - Gentillatre, Jacques, 1680-1740., 19 (Box 16)
      - Goujon, Jean., 1 (Box 16)
      - Ixnard, Pierre Michel d', 1723-1795., 1 (Box 16)
      - Le Brun, Charles, 1619-1690., 1 (Box 16)
      - Ledoux, Claude-Nicolas, 1736-1806., 8 (Box 16)
      - Lequeu, Jean-Jacques, 1757-c.1825., 1 (Box 16)
      - Mansard., 4 (Box 16)
      - Mansart, Jules-Hardouin, 1647-1708., 2 (Box 16)
      - Montfaucon, Bernard de., 1 (Box 16)
      - Perret, Jacques., 1 (Box 16)
    - Architectural ornament., 47 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous details., 12 (Box 16)
      - Louis XV., 23 (Box 16)
      - Louis XVI., 11 (Box 16)
      - Fountains., 1 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 72 (Box 16)
      Includes four folders of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Aix., 1 (Box 16)
      - Angouleme., 1 (Box 16)
      - Autun., 1 (Box 16)
      - Avallon., 1 (Box 16)
      - Avranches., 1 (Box 16)
      - Bapaume., 1 (Box 16)
      - Bayonne., 1 (Box 16)
      - Beaumesnil., 1 (Box 16)
      - Beaune., 1 (Box 16)
      - Beauvais., 1 (Box 16)
      - Boissy-Saint-Leger., 1 (Box 16)
      - Bonnivet., 1 (Box 16)
      - Bourg-Saint-Leonard., 1 (Box 16)
      - Brive., 1 (Box 17)
      - Cany-Barville., 1 (Box 17)
      - Champlatreux., 2 (Box 17)
      - Champs-sur-Mer., 1 (Box 17)
      - Charleville., 1 (Box 17)
      - Chastellux., 1 (Box 17)
      - Chateauneuf, Cote d'Or., 1 (Box 17)
      - Clermont-Ferrand., 2 (Box 17)
      - Colmar., 1 (Box 17)
      - Combourg., 1 (Box 17)
      - Coudray-Montpensier., 2 (Box 17)
      - D'Anet, Eure et Loire., 1 (Box 17)
      - Dinan., 2 (Box 17)
      - Eu., 1 (Box 17)
      - Flers., 1 (Box 17)
      - Fontaine-Francaise., 2 (Box 17)
      - Fontaine-Henri., 1 (Box 17)
      - Gradignan., 1 (Box 17)
      - Herecy (Allier)., 1 (Box 17)
      - Langeais., 1 (Box 17)
      - La Roche Courbon., 2 (Box 17)
      - Les Andelys, Eure., 1 (Box 17)
      - Les Baux., 1 (Box 17)
      - Loches., 1 (Box 17)
      - Luzarches., 1 (Box 17)
      - Maison Rouges., 1 (Box 17)
      - Mantes., 1 (Box 17)
      - Martigues., 1 (Box 17)
      - Maupertius., 1 (Box 17)
      - Mehun sur Vevre., 1 (Box 17)
      - Meillant., 1 (Box 17)
      - Mesnieres, Seine Inferieure., 1 (Box 17)
      - Monte Carlo (near)., 1 (Box 17)
      - Montsoreau., 1 (Box 17)
      - Olhain., 1 (Box 17)
      - Ormesson., 1 (Box 17)
      - Perigueux., 1 (Box 17)
      - Rigny-Usse., 2 (Box 17)
      - Saint Andre-des-Troyes., 1 (Box 17)
      - Saint-Illide., 1 (Box 17)
      - Saint Thegonnec., 2 (Box 17)
      - Sceaux., 1 (Box 17)
      - Tournan-en-Brie., 1 (Box 17)
      - Tremblay-Omonville., 1 (Box 17)
      - Trouville, Calvados., 1 (Box 17)
      - Val de Grace., 1 (Box 17)
      - Valognes., 1 (Box 17)
      - Vannes., 1 (Box 17)
      - Vendome., 2 (Box 17)
      - Verdun., 1 (Box 17)
    - Individual locations., 1283 (Box 17)
      - Abbeville., 5 (Box 17)
      - Acquiny., 2 (Box 18)
      - Amboise., 9 (Box 18)
      - Amiens., 2 (Box 18)
      - Anet., 3 (Box 18)
      - Angers., 4 (Box 18)
      - Arles., 5 (Box 18)
      - Arras., 2 (Box 18)
      - Auch., 3 (Box 18)
      - Auxerre., 3 (Box 18)
      - Avignon., 2 (Box 18)
      - Azay-le-Rideau., 21 (Box 18)
      - Balleroy, Calvados., 3 (Box 18)
      - Beaugency., 1 (Box 18)
      - Benouville., 2 (Box 18)
      - Besancon., 2 (Box 19)
      - Blerancourt., 3 (Box 19)
      - Blois., 73 (Box 19)
        - Miscellaneous buildings and architectural details., 16 (Box 19)
        - Chateau., 54 (Box 19)
          - Louis XII wing., 21 (Box 19)
          - Francis I wing., 28 (Box 20)
          - Gaston d'Orleans wing., 5 (Box 20)
        - Saint Vincent de Paul., 3 (Box 20)
      - Bordeaux., 16 (Box 20)
      - Bourges., 10 (Box 20)
      - Brissac., 4 (Box 20)
      - Cadillac., 1 (Box 20)
      - Caen., 26 (Box 20)
        - Miscellaneous buildings., 2 (Box 20)
        - Abbaye aux Hommes., 5 (Box 20)
        - Hotel d'Ecoville., 12 (Box 21)
        - Saint Pierre., 7 (Box 21)
      - Canon., 3 (Box 21)
      - Chambord., 34 (Box 21)
      - Chambourcy., 2 (Box 21)
      - Champ de Bataille., 6 (Box 21)
      - Champs., 3 (Box 22)
      - Chantilly., 28 (Box 22)
        - Miscellaneous drawings., 2 (Box 22)
        - Exterior., 18 (Box 22)
        - Interior., 8 (Box 22)
      - Chateaudun., 9 (Box 22)
      - Chaux., 17 (Box 22)
      - Chenonceaux., 14 (Box 22)
      - Cheverny., 7 (Box 23)
      - Compiegne., 11 (Box 23)
      - Dampierre., 3 (Box 23)
        Includes a folder of miscellaneous clipping.
      - Dijon., 10 (Box 23)
        - Miscellaneous buildings and interiors., 7 (Box 23)
        - Cathedral of Saint Michel., 3 (Box 23)
      - Dreux., 6 (Box 23)
      - Eaubonne., 2 (Box 23)
      - Ecouen., 5 (Box 23)
      - Ermenonville., 2 (Box 23)
      - Evreux., 1 (Box 24)
      - Fontainebleau., 100 (Box 24)
        - Chateau., 100 (Box 24)
          - Exterior., 45 (Box 24)
          - Interior., 55 (Box 24)
            - Miscellaneous interiors., 3 (Box 24)
            - Francois I., 7 (Box 24)
            - Henry II., 10 (Box 25)
            - Henry IV., 8 (Box 25)
            - Louis XIII., 5 (Box 25)
            - Louis XIV., 4 (Box 25)
            - Louis XV., 3 (Box 25)
            - Louis XVI., 9 (Box 25)
            - Napoleon (Empire)., 6 (Box 25)
      - Fontevrault., 1 (Box 25)
      - Foret de Dreux., 1 (Box 25)
      - Gif-sur-Yvette., 2 (Box 25)
      - Grand-Daubeuf., 1 (Box 25)
      - Grenoble., 4 (Box 25)
      - Guermantes., 2 (Box 26)
      - Harfleur., 2 (Box 26)
      - Haroue., 2 (Box 26)
      - Josselin., 4 (Box 26)
      - Jossigny., 2 (Box 26)
      - La Jarne., 2 (Box 26)
      - Langres., 1 (Box 26)
      - La Rochefoucauld., 4 (Box 26)
      - La Rochelle., 2 (Box 26)
      - Le Lude., 4 (Box 26)
      - Le Mans., 10 (Box 26)
      - Lille., 6 (Box 26)
      - Louveciennes., 6 (Box 26)
      - Luneville., 2 (Box 26)
      - Lyon., 2 (Box 26)
      - Maintenon., 7 (Box 26)
      - Maisons-Laffitte., 4 (Box 27)
      - Malmaison., 4 (Box 27)
      - Marly., 8 (Box 27)
      - Menars., 3 (Box 27)
      - Meudon., 4 (Box 27)
      - Milly., 5 (Box 27)
      - Moncley., 3 (Box 27)
      - Montpellier., 4 (Box 27)
      - Nancy., 20 (Box 27)
      - Nantes., 1 (Box 27)
      - Nantouillet., 1 (Box 27)
      - Neuilly., 3 (Box 27)
      - Nevers., 1 (Box 27)
      - Nice., 2 (Box 27)
      - Nimes., 1 (Box 27)
      - Nogent-les-Vierges., 3 (Box 28)
      - Noyon., 2 (Box 28)
      - O (near Mortree)., 4 (Box 28)
      - Orleans., 7 (Box 28)
      - Pagny., 1 (Box 28)
      - Paris., 353 (Box 28)
        - Miscellaneous plans and buildings., 16 (Box 28)
        - Streets., 1 (Box 28)
        - Chateaux., 5 (Box 28)
        - Churches., 54 (Box 28)
          - Miscellaneous churches., 4 (Box 28)
          - Pantheon., 12 (Box 28)
          - Saint Etienne du Mont., 9 (Box 29)
          - Saint-Eustache., 5 (Box 29)
          - Saint Gervais (Saint Protais)., 5 (Box 29)
          - Saint Sulpice., 6 (Box 29)
          - Sorbonne., 3 (Box 29)
          - Val de Grace., 10 (Box 29)
        - Fountains., 11 (Box 29)
          - Miscellaneous fountains., 5 (Box 29)
          - Fountain of the Medicis., 6 (Box 29)
        - Gates., 8 (Box 29)
          - Porte Saint Denis., 5 (Box 29)
          - Porte Saint Martin., 3 (Box 29)
        - Government buildings., 30 (Box 29)
          - Miscellaneous buildings., 2 (Box 29)
          - Barrieres., 7 (Box 29)
          - Hotel de Ville., 9 (Box 29)
          - Hotel des Monnaies., 4 (Box 29)
          - Palais de Justice., 8 (Box 30)
        - Hotels and houses., 89 (Box 30)
          - Miscellaneous buildings., 31 (Box 30)
          - Hotel Carnavalet., 4 (Box 30)
            Includes a folder of miscellaneous options.
          - Hotel de Choiseul., 2 (Box 30)
          - Maison de Fracois I., 2 (Box 30)
          - Hotel des Invalides., 19 (Box 30)
          - Hotel Jacquemart-Andre., 7 (Box 30)
          - Hotel de Salm., 8 (Box 31)
          - Hotel de Soubise., 12 (Box 31)
          - Hotel de Sully., 2 (Box 31)
          - Hotel Valette., 2 (Box 31)
        - Libraries., 2 (Box 31)
        - Museums., 39 (Box 31)
          - Louvre., 39 (Box 31)
            - Plans., 1 (Box 31)
            - General views., 6 (Box 31)
            - Exterior., 20 (Box 31)
            - Interior., 9 (Box 31)
            - Court., 3 (Box 32)
        - Palaces., 53 (Box 32)
          - Miscellaneous palaces., 3 (Box 32)
          - Luxembourg Palace., 21 (Box 32)
          - Palais Royale., 19 (Box 32)
          - Tuileries., 10 (Box 32)
        - Prisons., 2 (Box 32)
        - Schools., 12 (Box 32)
          For Beaux Arts see: Anet Chateau.
          - Miscellaneous schools., 1 (Box 32)
          - Anciens College des Ecossais., 1 (Box 32)
          - Ecole de Droit., 2 (Box 32)
          - L'Ecole de Medecine., 1 (Box 32)
          - Ecole Militaire., 5 (Box 32)
          - Institute de France (College of Four Nations)., 2 (Box 33)
        - Squares., 21 (Box 33)
          - Miscellaneous squares., 1 (Box 33)
          - Place de la Concorde., 9 (Box 33)
          - Place Vendome., 5 (Box 33)
          - Place des Victoires., 2 (Box 33)
          - Place des Vosges., 4 (Box 33)
        - Theaters., 9 (Box 33)
      - Passy., 4 (Box 33)
      - Pau., 5 (Box 33)
      - Plassac., 4 (Box 33)
      - Plessis-lez-Tours., 1 (Box 33)
      - Poitiers., 2 (Box 33)
      - Provins., 1 (Box 33)
      - Rennes., 3 (Box 33)
      - Rheims., 3 (Box 33)
      - Richelieu., 11 (Box 34)
      - Rochers., 1 (Box 34)
      - Rouen., 8 (Box 34)
        - Miscellaneous buildings., 6 (Box 34)
        - Chateau., 2 (Box 34)
      - Royaumont., 2 (Box 34)
      - Saint Andre de Cubzac., 2 (Box 34)
      - Saint-Andre-d'Hebertot., 2 (Box 34)
      - Saint-Cheron., 2 (Box 34)
      - Saint Cloud., 5 (Box 34)
      - Saint Denis., 1 (Box 34)
      - Saint Germain-en-Laye., 12 (Box 34)
      - Saint-Germain-de Livet., 2 (Box 34)
      - Saint-Malo., 3 (Box 34)
      - Sainte Marguerite., 2 (Box 34)
      - Saint Martin du Bec., 2 (Box 34)
      - Saint Remy., 2 (Box 34)
      - Saintes., 1 (Box 34)
      - Saulieu. (Box 34)
      - Saumur., 4 (Box 34)
      - Saverne., 1 (Box 35)
      - Sceaux., 3 (Box 35)
      - Selestat., 1 (Box 35)
      - Senlis., 2 (Box 35)
      - Strasbourg., 4 (Box 35)
      - Sully-sur-Loire., 4 (Box 35)
      - Tanlay., 3 (Box 35)
      - Toulouse., 17 (Box 35)
      - Tours., 6 (Box 35)
      - Tourville-en-Arque., 2 (Box 35)
      - Usse., 2 (Box 35)
      - Usson., 3 (Box 35)
      - Varengeville., 2 (Box 36)
      - Vaux-le-Vicomte., 24 (Box 36)
      - Versailles., 142 (Box 36)
        Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings.
        - Miscellaneous views., 3 (Box 36)
        - Bibliotheque., 2 (Box 36)
        - Chateau de Clagny., 4 (Box 36)
        - Chateau., 61 (Box 36)
          - Miscellaneous buildings., 6 (Box 36)
          - Plans., 8 (Box 37)
          - Air views., 3 (Box 37)
          - Exterior., 26 (Box 37)
            - Miscellaneous views., 12 (Box 37)
            - Paris facade., 4 (Box 37)
            - Garden facade., 10 (Box 37)
          - Interior., 18 (Box 37)
            - Miscellaneous views., 8 (Box 37)
            - Bedroom of Louis XIV., 3 (Box 37)
            - Queen's chamber., 2 (Box 37)
            - Galerie des Battailes., 3 (Box 37)
            - Galerie des Glaces., 2 (Box 37)
        - Chapel., 9 (Box 38)
        - Gardens., 21 (Box 38)
        - Grand Trianon., 10 (Box 38)
        - Petit Trainon., 24 (Box 38)
        - Hameau., 8 (Box 38)
      - Vichy., 1 (Box 38)
      - Villandry., 3 (Box 38)
      - Villarceaux., 1 (Box 38)
      - Villette., 3 (Box 38)
      - Vincennes., 5 (Box 38)
      - Vizille., 3 (Box 39)
  - Germany., 620 (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous buildings and architectural details., 6 (Box 39)
    - General architects., 2 (Box 39)
      - Neumann, Balthasar, 1687-1753., 2 (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous locations., 50 (Box 39)
      - Ahrensburg., 1 (Box 39)
      - Aldersbach, Bavaria., 1 (Box 39)
      - Alsfeld., 1 (Box 39)
      - Andechs., 1 (Box 39)
      - Bacharach., 1 (Box 39)
      - Banz., 2 (Box 39)
      - Blankenburg., 1 (Box 39)
      - Bonn., 1 (Box 39)
      - Budingen., 1 (Box 39)
      - Coblenz., 1 (Box 39)
      - Ebrach., 3 (Box 39)
      - Einbeck., 1 (Box 39)
      - Falkenlust., 1 (Box 39)
      - Freiburg., 1 (Box 39)
      - Fulda., 2 (Box 39)
      - Gossweinstein., 1 (Box 39)
      - Gotha., 1 (Box 39)
      - Heiligelinde., 1 (Box 39)
      - Kappel., 1 (Box 39)
      - Karlsruhe., 1 (Box 39)
      - Kassel., 1 (Box 39)
      - Kronberg., 1 (Box 39)
      - Landshut., 1 (Box 39)
      - Langenburg., 1 (Box 39)
      - Lorsch., 1 (Box 39)
      - Mainau., 1 (Box 39)
      - Mainz., 1 (Box 39)
      - Mannheim., 1 (Box 39)
      - Moritzburg., 1 (Box 39)
      - Neu-Hardensburg., 1 (Box 39)
      - Raitenhaslach., 1 (Box 39)
      - Rohr., 1 (Box 39)
      - Rottenbuch., 1 (Box 39)
      - Saint Blasien., 1 (Box 39)
      - Schaftlarn., 1 (Box 39)
      - Schleissheim., 4 (Box 39)
      - Schloss Nordkirchen., 1 (Box 39)
      - Schwabisch Hall., 1 (Box 39)
      - Seedorf., 1 (Box 39)
      - Tubingen., 1 (Box 39)
      - Waldsassen., 1 (Box 39)
      - Werneck., 1 (Box 39)
      - Wollenweberzunfthaus., 1 (Box 39)
    - Individual locations., 562 (Box 39)
      - Aschaffenburg., 1 (Box 39)
      - Augsburg., 5 (Box 39)
      - Bamberg., 6 (Box 39)
      - Bayreuth., 5 (Box 40)
      - Berg am Laim., 6 (Box 40)
      - Berlin., 20 (Box 40)
        - Miscellaneous buildings., 14 (Box 40)
        - Brandenburg Gates., 6 (Box 40)
      - Birnau., 8 (Box 40)
      - Breslau., 2 (Box 40)
      - Bruhl., 13 (Box 40)
      - Brunswick., 5 (Box 40)
      - Charlottenberg., 1 (Box 40)
      - Cologne., 8 (Box 40)
      - Diessen am Ammersee., 5 (Box 41)
      - Dinkelsbuehl., 1 (Box 41)
      - Dresden., 40 (Box 41)
        - Miscellaneous buildings and views., 19 (Box 41)
        - Catholic Church of the Court., 3 (Box 41)
        - Zwinger Palace., 18 (Box 41)
      - Dusseldorf., 8 (Box 41)
      - Ensisheim., 2 (Box 41)
      - Ettal., 6 (Box 41)
      - Frankfurt., 3 (Box 41)
      - Fraustadt., 2 (Box 41)
      - Freising., 9 (Box 42)
      - Gunzburg., 8 (Box 42)
      - Hamburg., 2 (Box 42)
      - Hameln., 1 (Box 42)
      - Hanover., 3 (Box 42)
      - Heidelberg., 28 (Box 42)
        - Miscellaneous buildings and views., 8 (Box 42)
        - Castle., 20 (Box 42)
      - Heilbronn., 1 (Box 42)
      - Herren-Chiemsee., 2 (Box 42)
      - Hildesheim., 15 (Box 42)
        - Miscellaneous buildings., 4 (Box 42)
        - Kaiser Haus., 2 (Box 42)
        - Roland's Hospital., 5 (Box 42)
        - Wedekind'sches House., 4 (Box 42)
      - Ingolstadt., 3 (Box 42)
      - Leipzig., 1 (Box 42)
      - Lubeck., 3 (Box 43)
      - Ludwigsburg., 6 (Box 43)
      - Luneburg., 1 (Box 43)
      - Magdeburg., 1 (Box 43)
      - Muhlhausen., 1 (Box 43)
      - Munich., 58 (Box 43)
        - Miscellaneous buildings., 10 (Box 43)
        - Amaliensburg Castle., 4 (Box 43)
        - Nymphenburg Palace., 8 (Box 43)
        - Residence., 18 (Box 43)
          Includes a treatise in German about the Residence.
        - S. Anna am Lehel., 2 (Box 43)
        - S. John Nepomuk., 10 (Box 43)
        - Theatrine Church., 6 (Box 44)
      - Munster., 5 (Box 44)
      - Neresheim., 7 (Box 44)
      - Nuremburg., 10 (Box 44)
      - Obermarchtal., 3 (Box 44)
      - Osterhofen., 8 (Box 44)
      - Ottobeuren., 13 (Box 44)
      - Pillnitz-an-der-Elbe., 3 (Box 44)
      - Pommersfelden., 9 (Box 44)
      - Potsdam., 35 (Box 44)
        - Miscellaneous buildings and views., 9 (Box 45)
        - New Palace., 12 (Box 45)
        - Sanssouci Palace., 14 (Box 45)
      - Regensburg., 1 (Box 45)
      - Rhens., 1 (Box 45)
      - Rohr., 7 (Box 45)
      - Rothenburg., 5 (Box 45)
        - Miscellaneous buildings., 1 (Box 45)
        - Rathaus., 4 (Box 45)
      - Rott am Inn., 13 (Box 45)
      - Schussenried., 6 (Box 46)
      - Steinhausen., 12 (Box 46)
      - Stolberg., 1 (Box 46)
      - Stuttgart., 8 (Box 46)
      - Trier., 2 (Box 46)
      - Vierzehnheiligen., 9 (Box 46)
      - Veitshochheim., 2 (Box 46)
      - Weingarten., 7 (Box 46)
      - Weltenburg., 13 (Box 46)
      - Wibligen., 6 (Box 47)
      - Wies., 26 (Box 47)
      - Wiesbaden., 2 (Box 47)
      - Weissenau., 6 (Box 47)
      - Wilhelmshohe., 4 (Box 47)
      - Wismar., 2 (Box 47)
      - Wolfenbuttel., 1 (Box 48)
      - Wurzburg., 32 (Box 48)
        - The Residence., 32 (Box 48)
      - Zweifalten., 13 (Box 49)